Guide to the New York University Department of History Oral History Class Collection OH.033
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III. 1984 Oral History Class Interview, 0.4 Linear Feet in 1 folder, 1 audiocassette, and 1 compact disc.
  This series contains one interview with a man who immigrated to the United States from Ireland in 1925 and worked as a longshoreman in New Jersey and New York. He discusses his immigration experiences and describes his work and experiences as a longshoreman in New Jersey and New York.
  - Burke, John, 1984 (Box 16, Cassette 153, Box 2, Folder 18, Box 7, Cd 20)
    John Burke was born in 1906 on a farm in County Galway, Ireland. He was one of 11 children. He immigrated to the United States (US) in 1925 and settled in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania before returning to Ireland in 1926. He immigrated again to the US in 1929 and settled in Jersey City, New Jersey (NJ). He worked as a warehouseman at the Western Electric Kearny Works in Kearny, NJ between 1929 and 1931 and held odd jobs between 1932 and 1933. He worked as a longshoreman from 1933 to 1948 or 1949, and became a foreman around 1948. He worked in different ports in NJ and New York. He was a member of the International Longshoremen's Association, Local 1247.
    This interview was conducted by Kathleen Doherty in 1984 at an unspecified location. The interview covers John Burke's working life. Burke discusses his experiences working as a warehouseman at the Western Electric Kearny Works in Kearny, NJ between 1929 and 1931 and working odd jobs after he was laid off in 1931. He recounts his first experiences working as a longshoreman, including the type of work that was available during the Great Depression and extortion of the new workers on the docks. He discusses the formation of the International Longshoremen's Association (ILA) Local 1247. He discusses the work patterns on the docks, the formation of work gangs, and pay rates for different types of cargo. He recounts becoming a foreman and the difference in work for longshoreman and foremen. He lists the different ports in which he worked: Hoboken, Jersey City, and Edgewater in New Jersey, and Staten Island and Brooklyn in New York. He explains the ways in which information was disseminated about which ports had work. Other topics include strikes and organized crime involvement in the ILA and on the docks.
    Duration: 1:02:26
    Stevedores -- New Jersey -- Interviews.
- Series IV. 1999 Oral History Class Interviews, 1.5 Linear Feet in 1 flat box and 1 half manuscript box.; 35 audiocassettes; 0.5 Linear Feet in 1 half manuscript box.
  This series contains interviews conducted by members of the oral history class led by Rachel Bernstain in 1999.
  This series contains interviews conducted with veterans of the Vietnam War, jazz musicians who played in New York City (NYC) between the 1940s and 1960s, members of the community garden movement in NYC, women in higher education in NYC, Italian immigrants, and anti-war activists. Field notes and indices are available for most interviews.
  - Ayers, Donald T., 1999 October 4; cuid513 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 1, Box 7, Cd 1-2)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:35:00, Sound
  - Barnes, Paula, 1999 October 20; cuid504 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 2, Cassette Tape 2 of 2, Box 10, Folder 24, Box 7, Cd 1-2)
    Content is from a telephone interview and there is a prominent electronic hum throughout.
    Cassette 1: Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:03:00, Sound Cassette 2: Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 00:37:00, Sound
  - Bert, Eddie, 1999 October 28; cuid512 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 2 of 2, Box 10, Folder 2, Box 7, Cd 1)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 00:40:00, Sound
  - Bradford, Eve, 1999 October 11; cuid509 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 3, Box 7, Cd 1)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 00:48:00, Sound
  - Castro, Rose Eduvigis, 1999 October 16; cuid516 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 4, Box 7, Cd 1)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:03:00, Sound
  - Crow, Bill, 1999 November 1 and 1999 November 8; cuid511 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 7, Cd 1)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:51:00, Sound
  - Davis, Doris, 1999 October 29; cuid519 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 6, Box 7, Cd 1)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:01:00, Sound
  - Diomede, Giovanni, 1999 October 20; cuid497 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 7, Box 7, Cd 1)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:04:00, Sound
  - D'Lugoff, Art, 1999 November 29; cuid510 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 8, Box 7, Cd 1)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 00:53:00, Sound
  - Eichner, Carolyn, 1999 October 10; cuid505 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 2, Cassette Tape 2 of 2, Box 10, Folder 9, Box 7, Cd 1-2)
    Cassette 1: Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:03:00, Sound Cassette 2: Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 00:10:00, Sound
  - Fischer, June, 1999 October 14; cuid503 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 2, Cassette Tape 2 of 2, Box 10, Folder 10, Box 7, Cd 1-2)
    On second cassette (Access Disc 2), a disconnected wire or a short caused an electronic hum throughout, making contect indecipherable.
    Cassette 1 Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:03:00, Sound Cassette 2 Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 00:06:00, Sound
  - Greene, Janet, 1999 December 10; cuid507 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 11, Box 7, Cd 1)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 00:59:00, Sound
  - Greenfield, Paula Abbebaum, 1999 October 2 and 1999 October 9; cuid518 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 2, Cassette Tape 2 of 2, Box 10, Folder 12, Box 7, Cd 1-4)
    Cassette 1: Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:35:00, Sound Cassette 2: Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:32:00, Sound
  - Henderson, Taja-Nia, 1999 September 27; cuid494 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 7, Cd 1)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:02:00, Sound
  - Kirby, Ellen, 1999 November 10; cuid508 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 2, Cassette Tape 2 of 2, Box 10, Folder 13, Box 7, Cd 1-2)
    Cassette 1: Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:04:00, Sound Cassette 2: Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 00:35:00, Sound
  - Kohl, Herbert, 1999 December 14; cuid522 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 14, Box 7, Cd 1)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 00:56:00, Sound
  - Lewis, Bob, 1999 November 17; cuid500 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 7, Cd 1)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:09:00, Sound
  - Mannetta, Tony, 1999 October 5; cuid501 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 7, Cd 1)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 00:37:00, Sound
  - Maxwell, Bill, 1999 November 15; cuid499 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 15, Box 7, Cd 1)
  - Padget, Ron, 1999 December 2; cuid521 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 16, Box 7, Cd 1)
  - Pernetti, Rose Mary, 1999 September 29; cuid517 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 17, Box 7, Cd 1)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 00:29:00, Sound
  - Pumphrey, Mary Ann May, 1999 October 30; cuid506 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 18, Box 7, Cd 1-2)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:26:00, Sound
  - Raber, Norman, 1999 November 1; cuid515 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 19, Box 7, Cd 1-3)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 02:15:00, Sound
  - Rosa, Ada, 1999 November 27; cuid496 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 20, Box 7, Cd 1)
  - Rosen, Marvin, 1999 October 16; cuid514 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 21, Box 7, Cd 1)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 00:52:00, Sound
  - Stern, Pnina, 1999 September 28; cuid502 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 2, Cassette Tape 2 of 2, Box 10, Folder 22, Box 7, Cd 1-2)
    Cassette 1 Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:03:00, Sound Cassette 2 Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 00:20:00, Sound
  - Tedeschi, Mario and Ann Tedeschi, 1999 September 18; cuid498 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 10, Folder 23, Box 7, Cd 1-2)
  - Terry, Bryant Thomas, 1999 October 22; cuid493 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 7, Cd 1-2)
    Format: Audiocassette, Duration: 01:32:00, Sound
  - Willis, Meredith S., 1999 December 8; cuid520 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 1, Box 7, Cd 1)
  - Wilson, Jaime J., 1999 October 15; cuid495 (Box 9, Cassette Tape 1 of 2, Cassette Tape 2 of 2, Box 7, Cd 1-2)